<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>test on Chloe Jo</title>
    <link>/evergreen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in test on Chloe Jo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 17:51:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/evergreen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Chinese Civil Examinations</title>
      <link>/evergreen/chinese-civil-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/chinese-civil-exam/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Disclaimer: So far the working note is based on this article.1
How did the Chinese Civil Examinations spread toward the west and how did it change the political landscape of the west? The bureaucratic problem created because of the civil service system? Or Civil service system can be seperated from the bureaucratic structure of the Chinese political system? The problem created because of the Civil Exam? E.g., talented people wasted their talents to become bureaucrats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geopolitics</title>
      <link>/evergreen/toc-geopolitics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/toc-geopolitics/</guid>
      <description>Generic Questions What specific geographical features influence international relations and global policy decisions? How has technology changed the way countries interact with each other? What strategies do countries use to overcome geographical limitations? Regional Interests Geopolitics of China Geopolitics of the Middle East </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDN(Content Delivery Network)</title>
      <link>/evergreen/content-delivery-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 11:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/content-delivery-network/</guid>
      <description>What is CDN A content delivery network (CDN) is a group of geographically distributed servers that speed up the delivery of web content by bringing it closer to where users are. Data centers across the globe use caching, a process that temporarily stores copies of files, so that you can access internet content from a web-enabled device or browser more quickly through a server near you. CDNs cache content like web pages, images, and video in proxy servers near to your physical location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geopolitics of China</title>
      <link>/evergreen/geopolitics-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/geopolitics-china/</guid>
      <description>What are the geopolitical interests of contemporary China China&amp;rsquo;s geopolitical interests include controlling access to the Strait of Malacca, which provides access to the world&amp;rsquo;s most important shipping lanes in the South China Sea; controlling access to Tibet and the Tibetan Plateau, which gives them access to the Tibetan sources of three of China&amp;rsquo;s great rivers, the Yellow, Yangtze, and Mekong; controlling access to the oil, minerals, precious metals, and markets of Africa; and maintaining amicable relations with Russia and other states along the Strait of Malacca and the South China Sea, while also protecting its territorial claims and interests in these regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS (Domain Name Server)</title>
      <link>/evergreen/domain-name-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/domain-name-server/</guid>
      <description>What is a DNS server A domain name server (DNS) is a server that translates human-readable domain names into the numerical IP addresses that computers use to communicate with each other on the internet. When you enter a domain name into your web browser&amp;rsquo;s address bar, your computer sends a request to the DNS server to look up the corresponding IP address for the website. The DNS server then responds with the IP address, and your computer uses that address to send a request for the website&amp;rsquo;s content to the appropriate server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geopolitics of the Middle East</title>
      <link>/evergreen/geopolitics-middle-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/geopolitics-middle-east/</guid>
      <description>Important player Iran Iran is a very mountainous country, which makes it hard to have an economy with all the different parts connected. There are lots of different minority groups living in Iran, each with its own culture and language. For example, Khuzestan is mostly Arab, and there are also Kurds, Azeri, Turkmen and Georgians. Most people in Iran speak Farsi, which is the language of the Persian majority. Because of this diversity, Iran&amp;rsquo;s leaders have usually used military force and a powerful security service to keep the country safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP)</title>
      <link>/evergreen/hyptertext-transfer-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/hyptertext-transfer-protocol/</guid>
      <description>What is HTTP Hyper Text Transfer Protocol (HTTP) is a protocol for transferring files on the World Wide Web. It is the foundation of data communication for the World Wide Web. It is a set of rules that defines how data is transmitted and formatted between web clients and servers. HTTP is a stateless protocol, meaning that each request and response are independent of each other and do not maintain any information about previous requests or responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transmission Control Protocol (TCP)</title>
      <link>/evergreen/transmission-control-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/transmission-control-protocol/</guid>
      <description>TCP (Transmission Control Protocol): A protocol that provides a reliable, ordered delivery of data over an IP network. TCP uses a three-way handshake to establish a connection and uses sequence numbers to ensure that data is delivered in the correct order.
TCP socket stream A TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) socket is a type of network socket that is used to create a connection between a client and a server. A socket is a software endpoint that establishes bidirectional communication between a server and one or more clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transport Layer Security (TLS)</title>
      <link>/evergreen/transport-layer-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/transport-layer-security/</guid>
      <description>What is TLS Transport Layer Security (TLS) is a cryptographic protocol designed to provide secure communication over a computer network. It is widely used in web browsers and other applications. TLS versions refer to the different versions of the TLS protocol, which have been released over the years and provide varying levels of security. The latest version is TLS 1.3, which was published in 2018.
The Process of TLS handshaking In the process of establishing an HTTPS connection, the client and server both exchange data about the TLS version, cipher algorithms, compression methods, certificates, and public keys in order to create a secure, encrypted connection using a symmetric key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happened behind the scene when you type an url and request the browser for information</title>
      <link>/evergreen/how-web-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/how-web-work/</guid>
      <description>parse the URL by first, check the protocol (usually HTTP), and retrieve the main (index) page (from &amp;ldquo;/&amp;rdquo;) the browser sends a request to a Domain Name Server translate the domain name into an IP address (the domain name server response with the ip address of the website) once the browser receives the IP address, opening of a socket (TCP socket) + TLS handshake (to establish the secure connection) browser send a GET request to the IP address for the website&amp;rsquo;s content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strait of Malacca</title>
      <link>/evergreen/strait-of-malacca/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/strait-of-malacca/</guid>
      <description>The Strait of Malacca is a narrow strait between the Malay Peninsula and the Indonesian island of Sumatra. It is one of the most important shipping lanes in the world, linking the Indian Ocean and the South China Sea, and carrying up to one-third of the world&amp;rsquo;s maritime trade, including oil and gas shipments from the Persian Gulf. The strait also plays an important role in geopolitics, as several countries in the region have strategic interests in controlling access to the strait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What specific geographical features influence international relations and global policy decisions?</title>
      <link>/evergreen/specific-geopolitical-features-influence-international-relationship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/specific-geopolitical-features-influence-international-relationship/</guid>
      <description>Geographical features that influence international relations and global policy decisions include physical landscapes such as mountains, deserts, rivers, jungles, lakes, and seas; climate; demographics; cultural regions; access to natural resources; power to defend land; air power; the internet; nation-forming; the Arctic; rivers and river networks; the Hindu Kush and the Himalayas; the rainy season; limited access to natural minerals or food sources; the legacy of colonial powers; and the technological genius and power projection of the last superpower standing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can history be completely remade? Has it ever happened in history? What is the limitation to this ambition?</title>
      <link>/evergreen/can-history-be-remade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/can-history-be-remade/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Chapter 3 of 1984 - Orwell, where Winston tries to remember what happened to his family and what happened in the past. However, the past was rewritten and the process of &amp;ldquo;rectifying&amp;rdquo; the history was vividly depicted in Chapter 4. However, to have the absolute power of dictate even the language requires real management skills and also a set of conditions&amp;hellip; I am curious how feasible it is in real life and what are conditions needed to make it happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Good and Evil - Ch1 Prejudices of Philosophers</title>
      <link>/evergreen/notes-beyondgoodandevil-ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/notes-beyondgoodandevil-ch1/</guid>
      <description>1. Nietzsche starts the first chapter of the book by questioning the &amp;ldquo;Will of Truth&amp;rdquo; - if there&amp;rsquo;s a will to truth, why not untruth? Nietzsche pointed that philosophers devoted themselves to the &amp;ldquo;Will of Truth&amp;rdquo; without questioning the origin of the will. He also mentioned such question is Dangerous.
Sphnix and Oedipus Sphnix is a mythical creature with a head of a human, the body of a lion and the wings of a falcon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strait of Hormuz</title>
      <link>/evergreen/strait-of-hormuz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/strait-of-hormuz/</guid>
      <description>The Strait of Hormuz is a narrow, strategically important waterway located between the Persian Gulf and the Gulf of Oman. It is the only sea passage from the Persian Gulf to the open ocean and is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most important oil chokepoints, with an estimated 21 million barrels of oil passing through it daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How has technology changed the way countries interact with each other?</title>
      <link>/evergreen/how-tech-change-the-way-countries-interact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 13:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/how-tech-change-the-way-countries-interact/</guid>
      <description>Technology has had a major impact on how countries interact with each other. For example, advances in communication technologies such as the internet, have made it easier for people to connect and share information across countries, allowing for faster and more efficient collaborations. In addition, advances in transportation technologies have enabled countries to interact more easily and quickly, allowing for increased trade, diplomatic exchanges, and travel. Finally, technology has also enabled countries to bridge the physical barriers that previously existed, such as the Himalayas and the Sahara Desert, which have historically separated nations and limited their ability to interact with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What strategies do countries use to overcome geographical limitations?</title>
      <link>/evergreen/what-strategies-do-contries-use-to-overcome-geographical-limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 13:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/what-strategies-do-contries-use-to-overcome-geographical-limitations/</guid>
      <description>Countries can use a variety of strategies to overcome geographical limitations. These can include utilizing technology to bridge physical distances, focusing foreign policy on regions that are more accessible and utilizing air and naval power to project power beyond their physical borders. They can also take advantage of existing geographical features, such as rivers and navigable seas, to facilitate trade and transportation. Additionally, countries may attempt to adjust their borders or create new ones to better manage their resources or protect their populations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
