<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on Chloe Jo</title>
    <link>/categories/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on Chloe Jo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Chinese Civil Examinations</title>
      <link>/evergreen/chinese-civil-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/chinese-civil-exam/</guid>
      <description>&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Disclaimer: So far the working note is based on this article.1
How did the Chinese Civil Examinations spread toward the west and how did it change the political landscape of the west? The bureaucratic problem created because of the civil service system? Or Civil service system can be seperated from the bureaucratic structure of the Chinese political system? The problem created because of the Civil Exam? E.g., talented people wasted their talents to become bureaucrats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geopolitics of China</title>
      <link>/evergreen/geopolitics-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/geopolitics-china/</guid>
      <description>What are the geopolitical interests of contemporary China China&amp;rsquo;s geopolitical interests include controlling access to the Strait of Malacca, which provides access to the world&amp;rsquo;s most important shipping lanes in the South China Sea; controlling access to Tibet and the Tibetan Plateau, which gives them access to the Tibetan sources of three of China&amp;rsquo;s great rivers, the Yellow, Yangtze, and Mekong; controlling access to the oil, minerals, precious metals, and markets of Africa; and maintaining amicable relations with Russia and other states along the Strait of Malacca and the South China Sea, while also protecting its territorial claims and interests in these regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geopolitics of the Middle East</title>
      <link>/evergreen/geopolitics-middle-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/geopolitics-middle-east/</guid>
      <description>Important player Iran Iran is a very mountainous country, which makes it hard to have an economy with all the different parts connected. There are lots of different minority groups living in Iran, each with its own culture and language. For example, Khuzestan is mostly Arab, and there are also Kurds, Azeri, Turkmen and Georgians. Most people in Iran speak Farsi, which is the language of the Persian majority. Because of this diversity, Iran&amp;rsquo;s leaders have usually used military force and a powerful security service to keep the country safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strait of Malacca</title>
      <link>/evergreen/strait-of-malacca/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/strait-of-malacca/</guid>
      <description>The Strait of Malacca is a narrow strait between the Malay Peninsula and the Indonesian island of Sumatra. It is one of the most important shipping lanes in the world, linking the Indian Ocean and the South China Sea, and carrying up to one-third of the world&amp;rsquo;s maritime trade, including oil and gas shipments from the Persian Gulf. The strait also plays an important role in geopolitics, as several countries in the region have strategic interests in controlling access to the strait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Good and Evil - Ch1 Prejudices of Philosophers</title>
      <link>/evergreen/notes-beyondgoodandevil-ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/notes-beyondgoodandevil-ch1/</guid>
      <description>1. Nietzsche starts the first chapter of the book by questioning the &amp;ldquo;Will of Truth&amp;rdquo; - if there&amp;rsquo;s a will to truth, why not untruth? Nietzsche pointed that philosophers devoted themselves to the &amp;ldquo;Will of Truth&amp;rdquo; without questioning the origin of the will. He also mentioned such question is Dangerous.
Sphnix and Oedipus Sphnix is a mythical creature with a head of a human, the body of a lion and the wings of a falcon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
