<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chloe Jo</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chloe Jo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CDN(Content Delivery Network)</title>
      <link>/evergreen/content-delivery-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 11:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/content-delivery-network/</guid>
      <description>What is CDN A content delivery network (CDN) is a group of geographically distributed servers that speed up the delivery of web content by bringing it closer to where users are. Data centers across the globe use caching, a process that temporarily stores copies of files, so that you can access internet content from a web-enabled device or browser more quickly through a server near you. CDNs cache content like web pages, images, and video in proxy servers near to your physical location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS (Domain Name Server)</title>
      <link>/evergreen/domain-name-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/domain-name-server/</guid>
      <description>What is a DNS server A domain name server (DNS) is a server that translates human-readable domain names into the numerical IP addresses that computers use to communicate with each other on the internet. When you enter a domain name into your web browser&amp;rsquo;s address bar, your computer sends a request to the DNS server to look up the corresponding IP address for the website. The DNS server then responds with the IP address, and your computer uses that address to send a request for the website&amp;rsquo;s content to the appropriate server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP)</title>
      <link>/evergreen/hyptertext-transfer-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/hyptertext-transfer-protocol/</guid>
      <description>What is HTTP Hyper Text Transfer Protocol (HTTP) is a protocol for transferring files on the World Wide Web. It is the foundation of data communication for the World Wide Web. It is a set of rules that defines how data is transmitted and formatted between web clients and servers. HTTP is a stateless protocol, meaning that each request and response are independent of each other and do not maintain any information about previous requests or responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transmission Control Protocol (TCP)</title>
      <link>/evergreen/transmission-control-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/transmission-control-protocol/</guid>
      <description>TCP (Transmission Control Protocol): A protocol that provides a reliable, ordered delivery of data over an IP network. TCP uses a three-way handshake to establish a connection and uses sequence numbers to ensure that data is delivered in the correct order.
TCP socket stream A TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) socket is a type of network socket that is used to create a connection between a client and a server. A socket is a software endpoint that establishes bidirectional communication between a server and one or more clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transport Layer Security (TLS)</title>
      <link>/evergreen/transport-layer-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/transport-layer-security/</guid>
      <description>What is TLS Transport Layer Security (TLS) is a cryptographic protocol designed to provide secure communication over a computer network. It is widely used in web browsers and other applications. TLS versions refer to the different versions of the TLS protocol, which have been released over the years and provide varying levels of security. The latest version is TLS 1.3, which was published in 2018.
The Process of TLS handshaking In the process of establishing an HTTPS connection, the client and server both exchange data about the TLS version, cipher algorithms, compression methods, certificates, and public keys in order to create a secure, encrypted connection using a symmetric key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happened behind the scene when you type an url and request the browser for information</title>
      <link>/evergreen/how-web-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/how-web-work/</guid>
      <description>parse the URL by first, check the protocol (usually HTTP), and retrieve the main (index) page (from &amp;ldquo;/&amp;rdquo;) the browser sends a request to a Domain Name Server translate the domain name into an IP address (the domain name server response with the ip address of the website) once the browser receives the IP address, opening of a socket (TCP socket) + TLS handshake (to establish the secure connection) browser send a GET request to the IP address for the website&amp;rsquo;s content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can history be completely remade? Has it ever happened in history? What is the limitation to this ambition?</title>
      <link>/evergreen/can-history-be-remade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/can-history-be-remade/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Chapter 3 of 1984 - Orwell, where Winston tries to remember what happened to his family and what happened in the past. However, the past was rewritten and the process of &amp;ldquo;rectifying&amp;rdquo; the history was vividly depicted in Chapter 4. However, to have the absolute power of dictate even the language requires real management skills and also a set of conditions&amp;hellip; I am curious how feasible it is in real life and what are conditions needed to make it happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Good and Evil - Ch1 Prejudices of Philosophers</title>
      <link>/evergreen/notes-beyondgoodandevil-ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/notes-beyondgoodandevil-ch1/</guid>
      <description>1. Nietzsche starts the first chapter of the book by questioning the &amp;ldquo;Will of Truth&amp;rdquo; - if there&amp;rsquo;s a will to truth, why not untruth? Nietzsche pointed that philosophers devoted themselves to the &amp;ldquo;Will of Truth&amp;rdquo; without questioning the origin of the will. He also mentioned such question is Dangerous.
Sphnix and Oedipus Sphnix is a mythical creature with a head of a human, the body of a lion and the wings of a falcon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Emacs for bookmark management</title>
      <link>/posts/using-emacs-for-bookmark-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 13:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/using-emacs-for-bookmark-management/</guid>
      <description>This post is inspired by Mike Zamansky&amp;rsquo;s video channel on youtube1.Since I am now using Arc as my main browser so usually I don&amp;rsquo;t usually need to manage my bookmark, sometimes when I saw interesting blogs and information, I still want to have it somewhere and preferably an annotation to tell me why I store it at the first place, to have this sort of bookmark in my emacs comes in handy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1984 - Orwell</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/orwell1984orwell2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/orwell1984orwell2020/</guid>
      <description>tags :
keywords Fiction / Classics,Fiction / Dystopian,politicalNovel Motivation for reading Having said so many times that my own country is rushing into the story of 1984 so many times I am finally reading the book in detail.
Background The book is published in 1949, but Orwell has more in mind than the anti-communist sentiments in the work. In Orwell&amp;rsquo;s thought, he found analogy between the British Labour Party and the Communist Party under Stalin and consider himself the left of the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Good and Evil</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/nietzschegoodevilprelude1907/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/nietzschegoodevilprelude1907/</guid>
      <description>tags Philosophy keywords morality author Friedrich Nietzsche Motivation for reading He&amp;rsquo;s the one that paved the way for existentialism, and he&amp;rsquo;s work is heavily referenced in Camus&#39; work&amp;hellip; I have long wanted to read about him.
Background Memo Quote Ch1-3 As little as the act of birth comes into consideration in the whole process and procedure of heredity, just as little is “being-conscious” as opposed to the instinctive in any decisive sense; the greater part of the conscious thinking of a philosopher is secretly influenced by his instincts and forced into definite channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Systems: A Programmer&#39;s Perspective</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/bryantcomputersystemsprogrammer2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/bryantcomputersystemsprogrammer2015/</guid>
      <description> tags ComputerScience/Testbook keywords SystemOperations </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes for The Brothers Karamazov</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/dostoyevskybrotherskaramazov2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/dostoyevskybrotherskaramazov2012/</guid>
      <description>tags Fiction/Classics author Fyodor Dostoevsky Motivation for reading Heavily referenced in Camus&amp;rsquo; Rabel.
Memo Quote Ivan&amp;rsquo;s view of the physical world and religion I have a Euclidian earthly mind, and how could I solve problems that are not of this world? And I advise you never to think about it either, my dear Alyosha, especially about God, whether He exists or not. All such questions are utterly inappropriate for a mind created with an idea of only three dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring org-protocol in AMD build MacOS</title>
      <link>/posts/emacs-config-org-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/emacs-config-org-protocol/</guid>
      <description>This is a post on configuring org-protocol for people using Emacs on MacOS with AMD chips. The documentary only contains configuration for up to MacOs built on Intel chips. I will also include the steps I have taken to figure the problem out with very limited programming and computer background knowledge.
First, load org-protocol.el to the init.el configuration file:
1(server-start) 2(add-to-list &amp;#39;load-path &amp;#34;~/path/to/org/protocol/&amp;#34;) 3(require &amp;#39;org-protocol) Note that org-protocol.el comes with the org-mode so it&amp;rsquo;s not in any package archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Configuration</title>
      <link>/posts/emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/emacs/</guid>
      <description>Rewrite my config to get rid of the redunant functions and build the system from stratch using straight.el for package management.
TODO Emacs configurations [4/7] ox-json + pyorg to obtain json data from org files, check org ele API also Install blink-search and explore it. Check on embark to see if it&amp;rsquo;s an alternative to which-key Install Projectile rewrite the super-agenda to make it nicer. improvement of performance of emacs (not really&amp;hellip; but I tried&amp;hellip;) reconfiuring eshell Setup before everything else 1(setq package-enable-at-startup nil) 2(setq fill-column 2000) Performance Monitoring Define a function that will monitor how long it takes for Emacs to startup:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Org &#43; Hugo &#43; Cloudflare for personal blog</title>
      <link>/posts/hugo-quick-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hugo-quick-start/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Quick setup Ox-Hugo Source of documentation:
ox-hugo manual for init.el Backlink 1(use-package ox-hugo 2	:after ox) Handing in org.file
I use one-page-per-post way to manage the post, the heading section looks the following:
1#+TITLE: 2#+AUTHOR: Chloe 3#+DATE: 2022-10-28 4#+HUGO_SECTION: posts 5#+HUGO_BASE_DIR:~/Blog 6#+HUGO_TAGS: 7#+EXPORT_HUGO_CATEGORIES: 8#+hugo_weight: auto 9#+HUGO_DRAFT: true 10#+hugo_auto_set_lastmod: t I use YASnipeet to generate the head section, so the date will be autogenerated to be the current date. Be aware that in ox-hugo, HUGO_BASE_DIR is mandentory, it determines where the root directory the exported .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Elisp 01 Functions</title>
      <link>/posts/emacs-lisp-01-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/emacs-lisp-01-functions/</guid>
      <description>Define a function Specify the `&amp;amp;optional` or `&amp;amp;rest` argument in the arguments
1 2(defun multiply-many (x &amp;amp;optional y &amp;amp;rest operands) 3	&amp;#34;Multiplying the result of math expression on the arguments X, Y and OPERANDS&amp;#34; 4	(dolist (i operands) 5	(when i 6	(setq x (* x 7	(or y 1) 8	i)))) 9	x) 10 11(multiply-many 2 3 8 19) Function wihtout names Lambda function - a function without a name</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Elisp 02 Variable and Scope</title>
      <link>/posts/emacs-lisp-02-variable-and-scope/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/emacs-lisp-02-variable-and-scope/</guid>
      <description>Variables Set vairbales and Define vairables are different Define Buffer-local variables Understanding variable scopes Creating Variable scope with let Defining and setting customization variables Variable is a symbol that binds with a value : &#39;tab-width-&amp;gt; 4
Set variables Variables are symbols binds to values, what setq means is &amp;ldquo;set quote&amp;rdquo;, a convient way to write
1 2(set &amp;#39;tab-width 4) 3 4;; The variable doesn&amp;#39;t have to exist or be pre-defined 5 6(set &amp;#39;i-dont-exist 5) Documenting Variables defvar allows one to assign documentations to the created variables</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Elisp 03 Reading and Writing Buffer in Emacs</title>
      <link>/posts/emacs-lisp-03-reading-and-writing-buffers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/emacs-lisp-03-reading-and-writing-buffers/</guid>
      <description>Basic API for Emacs Buffers Buffers may be visible or not.
Manipulating Buffer Current buffer 1(current-buffer) Get buffer by name or create one (get-buffer-create) 1 2(get-buffer &amp;#34;*scratch*&amp;#34;) Create a buffer if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t already exist:
1 2(get-buffer-create &amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34;) Changing the current buffer (set-buffer) 1(progn 2	(set-buffer (get-buffer &amp;#34;*scratch*&amp;#34;)) 3	(current-buffer)) 4 5;;equivalently 6(progn 7	(set-buffer &amp;#34;*scratch*&amp;#34;) 8	(current-buffer)) progn is an expression that allows you to run multiple expression inside of the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lisp Project - Dotcrafter</title>
      <link>/posts/emacs-lisp-00-final-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/emacs-lisp-00-final-project/</guid>
      <description>Use move-folder-to-config-files to move config folders into the /.dotfiles
Use move-file-to-config-files to move config files into the /.dotfiles
Use link-config-files to create symblink between the config files in the /.dotfiles and the home-directory
From function.org See: Interactive function
Define a command that automaticaly tangle the `.org` files in your dotfiles folder (this is used in the last section of the file.
(Not in actual production code)
1(defun 2	dotfiles-tangle-org-file(&amp;amp;optional org-file) 3	&amp;#34;Tangles a single .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 17:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>The page is still under construction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
