<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on Chloe Jo</title>
    <link>/status/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on Chloe Jo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/status/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prisoners of Geography</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/marshallprisonersgeographyten2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/marshallprisonersgeographyten2015/</guid>
      <description>Prisoner of Geography tags Geopolitics keywords History / World,Political Science / Geopolitics,Social Science / Human Geography Motivation for reading The book has been on my shelf for a while and I have always wanted to know more about international relationship from a geopolitical view.
About the author Tim Marshall is a British journalist and author. He is the former foreign editor at Sky News and the author of the best-selling book Prisoners of Geography: Ten Maps That Tell You Everything You Need To Know About Global Politics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Good and Evil</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/nietzschegoodevilprelude1907/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/nietzschegoodevilprelude1907/</guid>
      <description>tags Philosophy keywords morality author Friedrich Nietzsche Motivation for reading He&amp;rsquo;s the one that paved the way for existentialism, and he&amp;rsquo;s work is heavily referenced in Camus&#39; work&amp;hellip; I have long wanted to read about him.
Background Memo Quote Ch1-3 As little as the act of birth comes into consideration in the whole process and procedure of heredity, just as little is “being-conscious” as opposed to the instinctive in any decisive sense; the greater part of the conscious thinking of a philosopher is secretly influenced by his instincts and forced into definite channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Systems: A Programmer&#39;s Perspective</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/bryantcomputersystemsprogrammer2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/bryantcomputersystemsprogrammer2015/</guid>
      <description> tags ComputerScience/Testbook keywords SystemOperations </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
