<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bookshelves on Chloe Jo</title>
    <link>/bookshelves/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bookshelves on Chloe Jo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/bookshelves/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1984 - Orwell</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/orwell1984orwell2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/orwell1984orwell2020/</guid>
      <description>tags :
keywords Fiction / Classics,Fiction / Dystopian,politicalNovel Motivation for reading The book itself is well known by people in general but I have always always been one of which who never read the book before. Being well known as a dystopia book, the book is well known for depicting a despotism regime. And because of its reputation, I have been kept saying my own home country converging towards the world in 1984 in an accelerating book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Good and Evil</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/nietzschegoodevilprelude1907/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/nietzschegoodevilprelude1907/</guid>
      <description>tags Philosophy keywords morality author Friedrich Nietzsche Motivation for reading He&amp;rsquo;s the one that paved the way for existentialism, and he&amp;rsquo;s work is heavily referenced in Camus&#39; work&amp;hellip; I have long wanted to read about him.
Background Memo Quote Ch1-3 As little as the act of birth comes into consideration in the whole process and procedure of heredity, just as little is “being-conscious” as opposed to the instinctive in any decisive sense; the greater part of the conscious thinking of a philosopher is secretly influenced by his instincts, and forced into definite channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Systems: A Programmer&#39;s Perspective</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/bryantcomputersystemsprogrammer2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/bryantcomputersystemsprogrammer2015/</guid>
      <description> tags ComputerScience/Testbook keywords SystemOperations </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes for The Brothers Karamazov</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/dostoyevskybrotherskaramazov2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/dostoyevskybrotherskaramazov2012/</guid>
      <description>tags Fiction/Classics author Fyodor Dostoevsky Motivation for reading Heavily referenced in Camus&amp;rsquo; Rabel.
Memo Quote Ivan&amp;rsquo;s view of the physical world and religion I have a Euclidian earthly mind, and how could I solve problems that are not of this world? And I advise you never to think about it either, my dear Alyosha, especially about God, whether He exists or not. All such questions are utterly inappropriate for a mind created with an idea of only three dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
