<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>literatures on Chloe Jo</title>
    <link>/tags/literatures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in literatures on Chloe Jo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/literatures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Good and Evil - Ch1 Prejudices of Philosophers</title>
      <link>/evergreen/notes-beyondgoodandevil-ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/notes-beyondgoodandevil-ch1/</guid>
      <description>1 . Nietzsche starts the first chapter of the book by questioning the &amp;ldquo;Will of Truth&amp;rdquo; - if there&amp;rsquo;s a will to truth, why not untruth? Nietzsche pointed that philosophers devoted themselves to the &amp;ldquo;Will of Truth&amp;rdquo; without questioning the origin of the will. He also mentioned such question is Dangerous.
Background Sphnix and Oedipus Sphnix is a mythical creature with a head of a human, the body of a lion and the wings of a falcon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Good and Evil</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/nietzschegoodevilprelude1907/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/nietzschegoodevilprelude1907/</guid>
      <description> tags Philosophy keywords Existentialism Motivation for reading Memo Quote Background Impression Reading log &amp;lt;2022-11-16 Wed&amp;gt; : Reading Progress : 1% I was attempated to read it faster then realize I can&amp;rsquo;t understand anything if reading at that pace&amp;hellip; So my current goal is to read at least one section a day and build a more solid understanding of the book. &amp;lt;2022-11-16 Wed&amp;gt; : Reading Progress : 2% Ch1S2, Nietzsches questions why the values have to steam from good but not from evil more destructive motives&amp;hellip; but I don&amp;rsquo;t understand the meaning of the antithesis of value so I am very confused about the paragraph&amp;hellip; By chapter Ch1 Prejudices of Philosophers Relevant </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes for The Brothers Karamazov</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/dostoyevskybrotherskaramazov2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/dostoyevskybrotherskaramazov2012/</guid>
      <description>tags Fiction/Classics author Fyodor Dostoevsky Motivation for reading Heavily referenced in Camus&amp;rsquo; Rabel.
Memo Quote Ivan&amp;rsquo;s view of the physical world and religion I have a Euclidian earthly mind, and how could I solve problems that are not of this world? And I advise you never to think about it either, my dear Alyosha, especially about God, whether He exists or not. All such questions are utterly inappropriate for a mind created with an idea of only three dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
