<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>literatures on Chloe Jo</title>
    <link>/tags/literatures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in literatures on Chloe Jo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/literatures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Good and Evil - Ch1 Prejudices of Philosophers</title>
      <link>/evergreen/notes-beyondgoodandevil-ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/evergreen/notes-beyondgoodandevil-ch1/</guid>
      <description>1. Nietzsche starts the first chapter of the book by questioning the &amp;ldquo;Will of Truth&amp;rdquo; - if there&amp;rsquo;s a will to truth, why not untruth? Nietzsche pointed that philosophers devoted themselves to the &amp;ldquo;Will of Truth&amp;rdquo; without questioning the origin of the will. He also mentioned such question is Dangerous.
Sphnix and Oedipus Sphnix is a mythical creature with a head of a human, the body of a lion and the wings of a falcon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1984 - Orwell</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/orwell1984orwell2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/orwell1984orwell2020/</guid>
      <description>tags :
keywords Fiction / Classics,Fiction / Dystopian,politicalNovel Motivation for reading Having said so many times that my own country is rushing into the story of 1984 so many times I am finally reading the book in detail.
Background The book is published in 1949, but Orwell has more in mind than the anti-communist sentiments in the work. In Orwell&amp;rsquo;s thought, he found analogy between the British Labour Party and the Communist Party under Stalin and consider himself the left of the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Good and Evil</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/nietzschegoodevilprelude1907/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/nietzschegoodevilprelude1907/</guid>
      <description>tags Philosophy keywords morality author Friedrich Nietzsche Motivation for reading He&amp;rsquo;s the one that paved the way for existentialism, and he&amp;rsquo;s work is heavily referenced in Camus&#39; work&amp;hellip; I have long wanted to read about him.
Background Memo Quote Ch1-3 As little as the act of birth comes into consideration in the whole process and procedure of heredity, just as little is “being-conscious” as opposed to the instinctive in any decisive sense; the greater part of the conscious thinking of a philosopher is secretly influenced by his instincts and forced into definite channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes for The Brothers Karamazov</title>
      <link>/bookshelves/dostoyevskybrotherskaramazov2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelves/dostoyevskybrotherskaramazov2012/</guid>
      <description>tags Fiction/Classics author Fyodor Dostoevsky Motivation for reading Heavily referenced in Camus&amp;rsquo; Rabel.
Memo Quote Ivan&amp;rsquo;s view of the physical world and religion I have a Euclidian earthly mind, and how could I solve problems that are not of this world? And I advise you never to think about it either, my dear Alyosha, especially about God, whether He exists or not. All such questions are utterly inappropriate for a mind created with an idea of only three dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
